hey everyone welcome back to another
lesson in this car automation course
so in the last video i showed you how
you can use random values in your test
steps in order to make your test dynamic
right but in the process we also came
across an issue
where it was not able to perform a
particular operation on one of the
controls and hence the test failed right
so
the reason for this failure was more
than one control was found for that same
particular
element right and hence it was not able
to perform that particular operation
so
the element in contention was a radio
button right so
there are two radio buttons in the
application and both had the same
technical properties right and hence
tosca was not able to decide which radio
button it should click on
it so to resolve this kind of issues
right you have to
add more technical properties into your
elements right so
whenever you are trying to scan your
modules and if you come across some
elements which is not unique right or
which is not
where toska is not able to uniquely
identify that element you need to add
additional properties okay
or you need to change the identifying
mechanism okay so in this case we are
going to add another property which is a
technical property which will make this
control unique
and how we can do that we can do that by
rescanning our module okay
so tosca provides you
a way to rescan all your modules so that
if there are any changes in any
particular control or some control is
not able to
identify right then you can rescan the
module you can change the controls or
you can add additional properties to
your controls so that your tests are
running successfully right
so let's go to our module and this is
our module right so
select it and right click and there you
will find an option called rescan okay
so click on that and it should open up a
window
where it will show you all the
properties for your elements right
but before that i should have opened the
application otherwise you will see there
is no window found right
so let me just open up that particular
application
okay so this was the page which we were
trying to work upon and this was the
control the radio button which was not
working okay
so
let me
scan this again
okay so once i refresh it now you will
see um it will show up all the elements
which were selected and also the
elements other elements which are
present in this application okay
and the control which we are talking
about is this particular radio button
now if i select this radio button you
will see a orange pad being displayed
here which means the selected item is
not unique the message is given
right at the bottom
where you can easily see which controls
are unique and which controls are not
unique right
once you select this control
you will see here that uh the properties
are being displayed here right so
we should be taking care of the
technical properties because that's the
properties which is used by tosca in
order to identify your element right so
you can see there are two properties
currently selected one is name
and one is tag
but using these two technical properties
it is not able to identify your element
right
so
you can choose some more properties here
right so that is checked there is
disabled there is read only but you need
to be wise enough to choose the right
kind of property okay so just uh don't
go ahead and select any property but
choose the property which makes sense
right uh through which the tosca tool
can identify that particular element
right something like id name or anything
right
so in our case the name and tag is
already selected so i'll go ahead and
select this value okay
and once i select this value you will
see now the message has changed the
orange color sign has gone which means
my selected item is unique now right so
using these three properties it is
uniquely able to identify this element
right
so once it's this is done right uh now i
can click on save so that it can
save the changes and close this window
okay
now let's go back to our module and you
will see it has added another control
here right so it has not edited the
previous control which was added but it
has added new control and you can also
check the properties here there is an
additional property called value right
so
what i can do here is i can change the
name of this property so that i can
identify which control i am working with
right i will also go ahead and delete
this particular control here right
so
it will give me some warning
because it is already being used in one
of my test step but i will go ahead and
delete this right so that i am using the
right control in my module and the same
thing happens in my test case
okay
now if i come to test case
i need to perform some action on this
particular test step right uh this is
the new control which i have added
so
let me go and click this right
um there is some error here this is
probably because we have deleted that
particular control so let's go ahead and
delete this step right so these are all
the steps which we require in our test
okay so
once you do that right
we can now try and run this particular
test again
and see whether we are able to identify
the
control uniquely or not okay
so go to scratchbook and run it there
let me close this window so that it
opens up a fresh window
and now you will see the mouse pointer
went to the right control right
so there was no error right now because
tosca is able to identify the control
by using an additional technical
property
and the test passed right
so the application the account was
created successfully and all the test
steps also passed right
so this is a very
important thing whenever you are trying
to automate any application using tosca
because you will come across
many applications where you will face
this challenge where there are many
controls which have the same technical
properties so the first time you scan
your application uh you might not get
all unique elements okay so tosca can
identify some elements uniquely but it
may not identify all the elements
uniquely okay so you need to add some
additional technical properties which
are provided by tosca so that
those controls can be identified
uniquely when you are running your test
okay
so this is how you can rescan your
module how you can
add some more technical properties to
your controls and then run your test
successfully